Hello.
Next, we're going to add some controls to our player blueprint.
If we open it up.
I actually think that I made the camera a bit too close to my back.
So let's bring it on and maybe have a value of 1000 just so it's a bit further back.
Next if we head over to the graph.
Here's where we're going to write most of the code for how we control and how our cattle will behave.
We're want to do it just right click and look for jump.
So if you remember earlier, we made an actual mapping jump.
So it should be here.
Input, action, event jump.
Just select it.
And then just right click and look for move, Right.
So earlier we made an impact assessment called MOVE, Right.
Just select it.
So we'll make it so that when we press the jump on accountable jump and when we press the move right
on our character, move towards the right.
And using this node will also make it so our player character will move towards the left.
We press the left button.
So in order to make our character jump, when we press the jump down, we can just drag up here and
look for the jump node.
And this will just automatically make our player react to a jump up in the air.
When we release this one, you just want to drive off here.
Stop jumping.
And this will make it so our character will stop jumping next in order to make our player character
move towards the right or the left, we can just drag up here and add movement input.
So here, underwater action will determine where our character will move.
We're working with a 2D game.
And if we just go to the viewport and I set my sprite.
And I'm going to go to select and translate objects.
I'm just going to click this red arrow.
And as you can see, the value will move in the x axis.
So in order to the game or player character is always going to be moving in the x axis.
Because of this in our bank graph here under one direction, we just want this to have a value of one.
Then here on the scale value.
Just track off this access value and look for print string.
Oops.
So just right click and break the link here.
And I've got access to here.
Access to you here.
So if you remember earlier, we made it so that when we press the right one or the DD key, the access
value will be one.
And this will just make it so our character will move positively in the x direction.
However, we made it so that when we press the left button or the A button, this x value will be negative
one.
And that will just make it so our character will move negatively in the x axis.
So now we can just test our controls work.
So I'm going to go compile, close this and go play.
And spacebar.
My cat will jump by.
Press the right one.
My cat will move toward the right.
If I press the left hand, my character will move towards the left.
I just want to go over a couple more settings that we can do with the jump.
So if you wanted to play a character, to jump higher or you could do is go to character movement and
under details look for jump.
Velocity and it's here jumps the velocity.
If I made something like 600.
And go compile.
When my character jumps in the air or jump a lot higher.
And you wanted the play of character to have multiple jumps.
So right now our character can only jump once and then they can't jump again.
If you wanted to change that, you're going to play up.
And here on the jump, you're going to change the max jump count.
So I made this one like two.
Now my pet cat will be able to jump twice.
And if you want to make it so that the longer I hold the space bar on the high, my character is going
to jump.
We can do that with this handy little setting here.
So if we go to our BP currently, you can see jump Max whole time.
So I made this look like one.
I won't be able to hold my trombone for up to one second.
And as long as I'm holding the space pop band, my character will continuously move up.
So I'll showcase what I mean by go play.
And I just tap the jump off.
I just jump like that and then come back down.
However, if I hold my space bar one.
It's going to hold that jump and put.
But if you don't want to have that dynamic jump, then you can just set the jump Max count to be a value
of zero.
That's what we have to stop jumping.
If you have the jump max whole time above zero, then you need to ensure that you have the stop jumping.
And if you just leave it at zero, you don't really need to stop jumping around, but we'll just leave
it there.